"SONG CRIMINAL CODE"
ADULTERY AND RAPE ARE PUNISHABLE
BY 18 MONTHS OF PENAL SERVITUDE
IF INJURY OCCURS, THE PENALTY
IS INCREASED BY ONE DEGREE
ATTEMPTED THEFT IS PUNISHABLE
BY 50 LASHES WITH THE CANE
DEPENDING ON THE AMOUNT STOLEN,
THE PUNISHMENT MAY RANGE
FROM LASHINGS TO EXILE WITH HARD LABOR
THOSE WHO PRIVATELY MINT COINS
SHALL BE PUNISHED TO EXILE
OFFICIALS WHO ACCEPT BRIBES AND PERVERT
THE LAW ARE PUNISHED TO A CANING
CONSPIRACY TO MURDER A GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL
OR SUPERIOR IS PUNISHED BY EXILE
IF THE VICTIM IS INJURED,
THE SENTENCE IS EXECUTION BY HANGING
IF THE VICTIM IS KILLED,
THE SENTENCE IS EXECUTION BY BEHEADING
FOR OFFICIALS WHO EMBEZZLE OR STEAL
FROM THOSE UNDER THEIR SUPERVISION,
THE PENALTY IS THAT FOR ORDINARY THEFT
INCREASED BY TWO DEGREES
AT SUFFICIENT AMOUNTS,
THE PENALTY IS DEATH BY HANGING
THOSE WHO COMMIT MURDER SHALL BE BEHEADED
THOSE WHO KILL INTENTIONALLY
OR WITH A BLADE SHALL BE HANGED
IF A WEAPON IS USED,
REGARDLESS OF CIRCUMSTANCES,
IT SHALL BE TREATED AS MURDER WITH INTENT
The officials have arrived.
And what difference does it make?
Her life is ruined anyway.
Getting involved with that scoundrel,
she could only consider herself unlucky.
Since you care about her,
why don't you help her?
Isn't he just a constable?
Who did this to her?
The scoundrel from the coffin shop.
Every woman here has been ruined by him.
This time,
can we expect justice?
With witnesses and evidence,
he can't escape.
I'm tired.
I'm not running anymore.
Chasing at my heels,
like a dog.
Now it's your turn to run.
Son of a bitch.
Constable dog.
Dog...
Let me go!
Don't let him escape!
-Catch him!
What are you doing?
Catch him!
I work for the government.
Who would believe that?
-I work for the government!
-We can't let him take him away!
I work for the government!
What are you doing?!
My lord,
it's late and chilly.
Our humble shop has prepared some hot tea
for you to warm up.
I see.
Your son can stay here first.
Let's wait
until the case is cleared up.
Sir,
this isn't in accordance with the rules.
Rules?
What rules?
He has been accused of rape
and assault by the people.
According to the law, the suspect
should be arrested and detained.
Do I need you to teach me
how to handle a case?
Sir,
I'll bring the witnesses right now.
That courtesan wants an explanation.
Isn't this an explanation?
He really thinks too highly of himself.
Get out.
Get out!
My name is Xue Buyi.
I'm a constable.
I've been on duty for ten years,
and I've been a coward for ten years.
NOODLES
Here.
Erniang, let me help you.
You're here early today.
VINEGAR
You're always eating plain noodles.
Today, I made something different.
Do you want to try it?
I'm not used to anything else.
It's Bianliang style,
the taste of your hometown.
Erniang.
NOODLES
Landowner Wei,
here is the rent for you.
I'll move out in a few days.
Don't do it.
Where else can you go
without this noodle stand?
Your rent is too high.
I can't afford it.
It's not that I want
to make it difficult for you.
I truly care about you.
Look at your hands.
They're all calloused.
Wouldn't it be better
to live a good life with me?
You'd be much better off with...
You want to stand up for her?
Sure.
You...
can pay Erniang's rent
for the next few months.
-How much?
-Ten taels a month.
Give me three months' worth first.
Don't pick them up.
Don't say I didn't give you a chance.
That soy sauce.
For every flask you drink,
I'll subtract a tael of silver.
This is none of your business. Leave.
Please.
SOY SAUCE
Cut it out!
It's not like I have to stay here!
If you don't have the ability,
don't show off.
In the end,
you still have to rely on Erniang.
Don't take it to heart.
I may be useless.
But at least,
I want to keep this stand for Erniang.
Even if...
Excellent!
Lord Zhang is impressive!
Great footwork!
-Let's play another round!
-Come on!
Keep going!
Come on, sir!
Good!
Good-for-nothings.
Lord Zhang, have some water.
Sir, look.
Here.
Good!
Lord Zhang, fantastic!
Excellent!
Tell me, what do you want from me?
I want
to ask you to assign me a good job.
You've come to your senses.
I just want to earn some silver.
Wait for my word.
Take it to be washed.
TREASURY AND GRANARY
Did Jailer Zhang send you over?
For this flood disaster in Hedong City,
the court allocated
500,000 taels of relief funds,
all stored in our treasury.
You will split up into pairs
and start patrolling tonight
in shifts around the clock.
No mistakes are allowed.
That's all. Disperse.
Go back and prepare.
-All right.
-Let's go.
Foreman.
How is the pay
for guarding the treasury calculated?
You want more money?
Does the salary
from the state office not count?
You're quite handy.
I have no choice.
My kid keeps demanding it.
Which section are you from?
I was newly transferred
from the southern section.
You were in the outhouse for a long time.
I drank too much yesterday.
You really should drink less.
What did Jailer Zhang tell you?
Is there really no extra pay for this job?
Foreman,
this is a little token from our manager.
Enter.
Hey, here.
Who is this for?
Who do you think?
There are quite a few grain merchants
from Linzhou this time.
They all want to come out on top
to sell more stored grain.
Whoever pays more
naturally gets the business.
Taking this step
wasn't that hard after all.
Foreman.
Don't move!
This man broke into the treasury at night.
Tie him up quickly.
What are you doing? I'm one of you!
Sir.
Stay put.
Make it quick.
Then you'll suffer less.
Sir,
what is the meaning of this?
Isn't it clear enough?
The prefect of Pingyang City, Zhang Yuzhi,
secretly colluded with grain merchants
and conspired with bandit leaders
to steal 30,000 taels
of disaster relief silver
and was caught red-handed.
Do you
confess?
Sir,
if I were the inside man,
why would I risk my life
to catch that thief?
All the guards are dead,
and only you survived.
You snake.
Snake!
You should
help him.
Who are you?
I am the Inspector of Hedong City,
Li Zhen.
This case has been handed over
to the Criminal Investigation Department.
The suspect stays here.
You can leave.
I can't make the decision on this matter.
Go back and wait.
The suspect has confessed
with a fingerprint,
which is an admission of guilt.
What else is there
to investigate in this case?
Didn't you hear?
The magistrate has already
made a decision.
Judicial Commissioner Huang is here!
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION DEPARTMENT
Judicial Commissioner Huang.
Magistrate Yang.
I didn't know you were coming, Lord Huang.
I apologize for not coming out
to receive you.
Jailer Zhang,
prepare the wine.
Let's skip the wine.
I have some good tea.
Once the case is resolved,
I'll invite you for a cup of tea.
Then I will definitely accompany you
to investigate this case
and get to the bottom of it.
Lord Yang, you're busy
with official duties at the state office,
so there's no need
to trouble yourself with this case.
Lord Yang, please feel free to leave.
Do you admit your guilt?
I am being framed.
There are hidden sentries
outside the treasury.
Five miles north
is the military headquarters.
Once the signal arrow is fired,
reinforcements arrive in less than half
of an incense stick's time.
The sentry layout changes daily,
known only to the day's foreman.
Without an insider,
how could the bandits eliminate them all?
It was that bearded man.
Tell me more.
That bearded man claimed
to be a transferred constable.
I saw it with my own eyes.
He helped the bandits move
the relief silver.
He must have figured out the sentry layout
during patrols.
The person I caught
could easily handle the sentries,
given his agility.
I only
glimpsed the other person,
but he seemed strong,
as many guards had broken bones.
Only Jailer Zhang
could have planted the bearded man.
You're from Eagle Hall after all.
You kept your wits about you.
Buyi.
How have you been all these years?
Master,
I've disgraced you.
I know it's not easy for you.
But the court established Eagle Hall
to train iron-willed officers.
The current you
is indeed disappointing.
Master,
please give me another chance.
You caught the man.
Do you want to interrogate him?
Fei Erlang,
the Criminal Investigation Department
uncovered your identity,
so they can also find out
about the other two.
Confess quickly.
You officers
only have these tricks.
High-ranking officer,
I pulled off such a big job.
Why don't we
have a chat?
Let me try.
You're no good either.
Mister,
be careful when breaking ribs.
You could easily pierce the organs.
It's effective.
Buyi,
the Eagle Hall Code includes three tests,
capture, interrogation, and execution.
How many did you pass?
Master,
I only passed the "capture" test.
I don't believe
it's because you're incapable.
It's just that you have sentimental mercy.
So many years have passed.
I thought
you would have matured.
Seven-faced Fox
and Nine-patterned Dragon.
Are they your accomplices?
They asked me
to handle the sentries.
How much each earns
depends on our own ability.
Who is the bearded man?
Fox.
Was he sent by Jailer Zhang?
I don't know.
Did Yang Shouxin instruct you?
I...
Master, he's just a small fry.
The other two are key.
If I intervene in this case,
Magistrate Yang will definitely
seek assistance from above.
Catch those two bandits quickly.
Yes.
You can participate too.
Remember,
a thunderous approach is
the same as a compassionate heart.
The treasury theft case
requires thorough
and appropriate handling.
You're doing well.
Stop joking. I'm just an underling.
One word from above,
and we're running ourselves ragged.
Did you get married?
If I got married, wouldn't I tell you?
You didn't get married, did you?
Me?
When I'm like this?
Buyi,
no offense,
but you were amazing before.
Without you, there wouldn't be me.
You were just too stubborn.
If you had pleaded with the master,
you could have stayed at Eagle Hall.
This time, the master is testing you,
and it's an opportunity for you.
Take my advice.
Don't be as foolish as before.
How should we investigate further?
The silver isn't something
they can spend just as they wish.
They will definitely find someone
to fence the silver.
And it's not a small amount.
There aren't many places
that can melt it down.
Do you mean
the underground bank?
Who are you?
We're officials investigating a case.
You're government officials?
Do you know whose place this is?
I'll go check over there.
What are you doing?
Illegally minting copper coins
is a serious crime.
I'll give you a chance.
Have you seen him?
I haven't.
Have you heard of Nine-patterned Dragon
and Seven-faced Fox?
ACCOUNT BOOK
What's going on?
Sir,
we are all disaster victims,
just trying to find some work to survive.
Please, let us go.
The case is more urgent.
To hell with you!
Screw you!
-Who told you to speak?
-Stop, please!
I was wrong!
-Blabbermouth!
-Stop it!
I've had enough of these miscreants.
You knew about the underground bank
all along, didn't you?
Yes, I knew.
What did you find?
Just wait.
The clues will come to us.
Oh, you!
It's all with your blessing.
Hey, here they come.
Have a seat.
Sit.
Let me introduce them to you.
These are my disciples.
Li Zhen and Xue Buyi.
Landowner Wei.
Do you know each other?
Quite well.
What a coincidence!
The underground bank you just searched
belongs to Landowner Wei.
Tell Landowner Wei what you think.
Look familiar?
ACCOUNT BOOK
Lord Huang, didn't you say earlier
that today isn't about official business,
only friends?
That depends on
whether you want to be my friend.
Please, Lord Huang.
Our master doesn't drink.
Today,
I just want some information.
Your underground banks
are all over Pingyang City.
The clues to the treasury theft
might be there.
Please write down the locations
of all the underground banks.
Lord Huang,
I just help with bookkeeping
and have never been involved
in the underground bank business.
I don't know about these things.
Landowner Wei, don't fret.
Drink this cup of liquor.
Perhaps
you will remember something.
I don't drink either.
Why don't you let me--
Then drink soy sauce.
-Waiter.
-No need.
I remember now.
What do you think
we are working for?
Just follow our master.
-Take a look over here.
-Yes.
Power will come.
Officer, this is a gift for you.
Wealth will come.
NOODLES
Previously, the rent was too high.
From now on, it's one tael per month.
Dignity will come too.
This was found in the underground bank.
The other half has already been melted.
Did you find the source?
The coffin shop in the east section.
Bring the culprit to see me
within three days.
What are you doing here again?
I'll ask only once.
Where did this come from?
Official silver
naturally came from the court.
Official silver.
Tell us!
The dye house.
The man had a strong dye smell.
What did he look like?
He deliberately covered his face.
How would I know what he looks like?
Think again.
That man has a powerful grip.
He broke one of the workers' arms
with his bare hands.
Buyi.
Seven-faced Fox.
Nine-patterned Dragon.
Let's go.
Wait.
Every woman here has been ruined by him.
This time,
can we expect justice?
Take it.
Are you resisting arrest?
Did you see it?
Of course.
My face!
You two,
go check over there.
That man has a powerful grip.
Nine-patterned Dragon.
Run!
Catch!
Buyi,
you were slow.
It's been too long without practice.
I'm rusty.
Go!
Not here.
GOOD FORTUNE FIREWORKS AND FIRECRACKERS
So this
is what Seven-faced Fox means.
Is there any benefit
from this task?
No.
Erniang,
everyone says your noodles are delicious,
and they'll be coming back often.
If you ever need anything,
just ask...
So delicious.
Everyone, dig in.
-Sure.
-Of course.
NOODLES
Leave them.
They can handle it themselves.
This landlady is a good cook
and has a kind heart.
Give it to me.
She just doesn't smile.
The noodles are good.
But she doesn't treat you very well.
-Let's not talk about it.
-Oh, you're blushing.
All right.
I was just thinking.
First, it was a bearded man,
then a young lady.
This Seven-faced Fox
must have at least five more faces.
The escalating treasury embezzlement case
now demands urgent resolution.
As long as he's a human,
he can't escape.
How do you plan to catch him?
Sir, may I have a word
with you in private?
Just say it.
This is my brother.
The message is from above.
You guys eat.
I'm going to relieve myself.
That night, I realized
that the respect others gave me
was because of Li Zhen.
I wanted to prove to everyone
that I
deserve their respect.
Have you seen this sachet before?
No, I haven't.
RUYI BROCADE SHOP
MASTER SHOULIU
NANCHENG TAILOR SHOP
Shopkeeper.
This is mine.
Kid,
I found this at the door.
Is it yours?
No, it's not. Mine is here.
Xiao Chong.
Xiao Chong!
You're back.
Sorry, I used your outhouse.
Where's my child?
Is that your child?
What have you done to him?
He's fine for now.
Have all the underground banks
been searched?
Yes.
But no clues
about the Seven-faced Fox were found.
Where did Xue Buyi go?
We've been acting separately lately,
so I'm not sure.
Acting separately?
Master.
He's the Seven-faced Fox.
Are you sure?
I've interrogated him.
The mastermind is Yang Shouxin.
Yes.
How was he caught?
I'm slow-witted,
unlike my junior,
so it took more time.
I went door to door to find him.
As long as Seven-faced Fox testifies
against Yang Shouxin,
it will be ironclad evidence.
How can you ensure
he won't recant in court
and put us in a perilous position?
Master,
I remembered everything you taught me.
I have my ways
to make him comply.
Yang Shouxin has gathered
a group of loyal warriors in his mansion.
He must know
that Seven-faced Fox has been caught.
Those who resist,
kill without mercy!
-Yes!
I've long heard
that Lord Huang's guards are brave
and decisive in battle.
Today, I see
that it's true.
Lord Yang, are you implying
that I used my guards
to kill innocents indiscriminately?
Isn't that so?
Lord Yang, you've misunderstood.
I always comply with legal reasoning.
The Judicial Censor is here!
Lord Yang is the city magistrate.
I am the Judicial Commissioner
of the Hedong Circuit.
The theft of disaster relief silver
is a major issue.
Lord Yang and I are responsible
for explaining it to the court.
Since the Judicial Censor is here
to inspect the eight prefectures,
I will clear this case
in front of him.
Bring the person up.
The criminal, Seven-faced Fox,
broke into the treasury at night,
killed the guards,
and stole the disaster relief silver.
Am I correct?
It's what I did.
Who instructed you?
Yang Shouxin.
Are you referring to the magistrate here?
Exactly.
He has been secretly fighting
with the prefect for a long time.
He sent me to steal the silver
to frame the prefect
and bring him down.
Do you have any evidence?
The luminous glass lamp
lost at Yanchi Pavilion three months ago,
the Golden Buddha statue
lost at Xiaoyun Tower a year ago,
and the coiled dragon jade
excavated from the Han King's tomb
three years ago
were all stolen by me.
He likes to collect rare items.
They should all be in his mansion.
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION DEPARTMENT
Lord Yang,
how do you explain this?
My lord, what do you think?
I must trouble you, Lord Huang,
to escort him back to the capital.
The Court of Judicial Review has ways
to make him confess to the crime.
Thank you for your efforts.
Lord Huang,
you and I serve in the same court.
You should know the rules
of the officialdom.
In this matter,
I am just a pawn.
My words don't count.
As for the hand that moves the pawns...
I've heard Lord Huang is skilled in chess.
Which pawns to take and which not to,
I need not say.
Excellent Xiaofengtuan.
Superior tea.
Lord Huang, we can discuss any terms
you have.
The main culprit, Yang Shouxin,
committed suicide out of guilt.
And his accomplice, the Seven-faced Fox,
seized a blade during the chaos
and was killed on the spot.
-How is it?
-This is done.
What's wrong, Buyi?
Are we solving a case or dividing spoils?
Only if you take it
are you one of us.
I've never seen so much.
Buyi.
You handled this case well.
Come back to Bianliang City with me.
Thanks for your guidance, Master.
Even a small place like Pingyang City
has so much strife.
Bianliang City
will be even more dangerous.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
From now on,
I'll follow your instructions.
Now that the Seven-faced Fox
has been brought to justice,
there's no need
to keep the child, is there?
Find an abandoned body of similar size,
preferably from the last two days.
You've come this far.
Buyi,
don't be foolish.
He's just a child.
All right.
You need to get used to it.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to help you.
We've been brothers for so many years.
Can you let me off
just this once?
That's why I can't let you do this.
Buyi,
this isn't that hard.
Li Zhen!
I beg you to let the child go!
Buyi,
have you forgotten?
How many brothers
did we kill at his age
to stay at Eagle Hall?
Our hands
are already stained with blood.
I had no choice in the past.
We still have no choice now!
I will tell Master
that you killed the child.
From now on,
don't be foolish anymore.
What did the child do wrong?
Wake up, Li Zhen!
It was an accident.
I didn't mean to kill him.
I just wanted him to understand
that I couldn't follow
his path.
NOTICE FROM PINGYANG PREFECTURAL OFFICE
It's him.
Looking like this?
You said he killed a court official?
That's what the wanted notice says.
Isn't that him in the drawing?
Take him away!
What's wrong?
He's the one who saved you?
Isn't he an officer?
Let's go.
He's a troublemaker.
All right.
Sorry.
So you're not dead yet.
When you were swaggering
behind Huang Shining,
did you ever think of today?
Erniang should see what you look like now.
Look at you!
Let's go.
He won't die.
Don't delay the government's work.
These disaster victims are quite loyal.
It's a pity.
They don't even know
they're at death's door.
What do you mean?
Let me tell you,
dozens of people in the Yang household
were killed by Huang Shining and his men.
But Huang Shining thought
that wasn't enough.
Just getting rid of Yang Shouxin
wasn't enough!
He wants a great achievement!
What nonsense are you talking about?
Nonsense?
Yang Shouxin was labeled a rebel,
and I suffered because of it.
You probably don't know, do you?
All those people in the underground banks
of Pingyang City were silenced!
The fact that Huang Shining
has reached where he is today
is inseparable from you!
You still dare to kick me?
Huang Shining wants
to use the heads of those disaster victims
to cement the charge
of inciting rebellion!
Those victims are being sent
to their deaths!
You've fallen to this state
and have no other way out.
You might as well leave the city with me.
I'll find someone to treat your injuries.
In return, you protect me,
and you'll have a meal to eat.
WANTED
NOODLES
VINEGAR
Don't push! One at a time!
Let me have a look.
What's your name?
-I'll do any work.
-I can too.
I've got plenty of strength.
Stop looking. Don't cause trouble for me.
Hurry up.
How many people are there below?
There are already over 100.
That's enough.
Let's do it tonight.
The remnants
of Yang Shouxin's rebel faction
gathered 1,000 people on the evening
of the Dingmao day in the Shen month,
intending to stage a rebellion.
Huang Shining,
the judicial commissioner
of the Hedong Circuit,
personally led the guards
to suppress the rebellion
and beheaded 100 bandits,
vowing to ensure local peace.
The medicine might hurt,
but it works.
Leaving
might not be shameful.
But I can't get past
that hurdle in my heart.
I...
don't want to hide anymore.
If you want to go to your death,
I won't stop you.
It's always unpleasant
when I see you anyway.
This time,
don't let that old scoundrel
have his way either!
Go!
Huang Shining!
You are here.
Come.
Have a drink with me.
Stop pretending!
All of Pingyang City will know
what kind of person you are.
People only care about themselves.
No one cares about the truth.
The truth
is the story told by the victors.
If you leave,
you'll just be an ordinary fugitive.
But you came back.
That makes you the rebel leader.
The story is perfect.
For your own selfish gain,
you harm the innocent.
-Do you still consider yourself a human?
-And you?
Ten years in service,
and you have nothing.
You live worse than a dog!
Do you consider yourself a human?
Filthy old bastard!
That's not how I taught you.
Too light!
Too slow!
Too obvious!
Now that looks a bit more like it.
Instead of being an eagle in the sky,
you insist on being a dog!
Eagle or dog,
a beast is just a beast!
I am Huang Shining, judicial commissioner
of the Hedong Circuit!
Tonight, there was a rebellion,
and I brought people here to fight!
This person is the rebel leader.
Arrest him!
Buyi,
watch closely.
This is
the last lesson I will give you.
It's not that I don't understand.
It's that I'm different from you.
Where did the suspect go?
Search thoroughly!
It seems someone in the court
couldn't stand it anymore.
In the end, Huang Shining was just a pawn.
The court has withdrawn
the warrant for your arrest.
There's also news
that you'll be rewarded soon.
Anyway, I'm going back.
Say something, will you?
Huang Shining, the judicial commissioner
of the Hedong Circuit,
held a high position,
but instead of serving the country
and caring for the people,
he sought to massacre disaster victims
and fabricate signs of rebellion
for personal gain.
Yang Shouxin, the magistrate of Pingyang,
was loyal and brave
and saw through the treachery,
-but unfortunately, he met his demise.
-What's over there?
-Fortunately, heaven does not
-There's a notice.
abandon the loyal.
The court established Eagle Hall
to train iron-willed officers.
The Eagle Hall Code includes three tests.
Capture.
Cast the net wide
to capture the mastermind.
Better harsh than too forgiving.
Interrogation.
Master the art of cunning.
Strike with thunderous force.
Expose their treachery.
Execution.
Hold fast to the path of righteousness.
Root out evil to its core.
There is no room
for sentiment before the law.
Buyi,
how many did you pass?
I only passed the "capture" test.
I don't believe
it's because you're incapable.
Get out!
It's just that you have sentimental mercy.
EAST SIDE COFFIN SHOP
Did you get married?
You didn't get married, did you?
Me?
When I'm like this?
You were just too stubborn.
If you had pleaded with the master,
you could have stayed at Eagle Hall.
Come back to Bianliang City with me.
In the past, so many descendants
of noble families
and meritorious generals
were named
Buyi.
Do not forget your past.
Eagle Hall is your foundation.
NOODLES
And Bianliang City is your true home.
PLAIN NOODLES
It's Bianliang style,
the taste of your hometown.
But even so, it's nothing more
than using power to oppress others.
Bianliang
or Pingyang,
what difference does that make?
Have you forgotten?
Our hands
are already stained with blood.
I had no choice in the past.
Do you truly wish to return?
One, two, three.
One, two, three, go.
Go.
One, two, three.